Xiaojing Deng

Phone: 216-534-3362 | Email: 8redfishcreative@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/xiaojing-deng-b04160248

GitHub: https://github.com/xiaojing168jmg168
Portfolio: https://xiaojing-deng.herokuapp.com

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a 10-year background in graphic design and e-commerce. Effective in combining design principles and problem-solving with a desire to deliver user-friendly applications and software. Proficiency in using the MERN Stack. Recently earned a Certificate in Full Stack Flex Web Development from Case Western Reserve University.

Technical Skills

Back-end Tech: Restful APIs, GraphQL, MongoDB (Mongoose ODM), MySQL (Sequelize),

Express, Node.js

Front-end Tech: Handlebars.js, React, HTML, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS, Sass

Stack: MERN Stack.

Applications: MongoDB, Atlas, GraphQL

Work Experience

8 RED FISH CREATIVE, CO-OWNER

Lakewood, Ohio. October 2013 – Present

- Actively manage two online Etsy stores as part of a two-person partnership.
- Print and fulfill orders for a yearly average of 600+ buyers.
- Using hand-painted items, Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator, developed a watercolor-design kit for the graphic design/digital creative community.

NENG JING WEB SERVICES. LTC OWNER

Shenzhen, China, June 2003 – November 2008

- As owner, specialized in web-based solutions for 500 Shenzhen businesses.
- Managed a staff of 10-15 employees including 4 web designers.

Education

Full Stack Flex Web Development Boot Camp Certificate: Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio. August 2022 – February 2023

Associate degree in Accounting: Wuhan University of Finance and Economics, Wuhan, China. September 1997 – July 2000

Projects

8 Red Fish Creative | https://github.com/xiaojing168jmg168/8-red-fish-creative | https://eight-red-fish-creative.onrender.com (in development)

- 8 Red Fish Creative is an E-commerce app built from the ground up. Implemented
 features such as user authentication, product listing, search, shopping cart, and checkout
 using Stripe/PayPal payment gateway.
- Core responsibilities: A fully functioning website using MERN stack.
- Technologies: React, Context, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose.

Cars-R-Us | https://github.com/xiaojing168jmg168/cars-r-us | https://floating-river-45182.herokuapp.com

- Cars-R-Us is a website that allows users to advertise information about a car they wish to sell and provide ways for buyers to contact them about the car.
- **Core responsibilities:** Front-end. Built responsive, interactive web pages using Handlebars.js, CSS, and JavaScript. Enhanced user experience with CSS animations.
- **Technologies:** Handlebars.js, Express, Node, MySQL(Sequelize), Bcrypt and Bootstrap.

Tech Blog | <u>https://github.com/xiaojing168jmg168/tech-blog-mvc | </u><u>https://tech-blog-xiaojing.herokuapp.com</u>

- A Tech Blog that allows users to login and sign up to create new posts. Posts are editable and can be deleted by the author. Logged-in users can leave comments.
- Core responsibilities: Design, develop, and deploy a fully functioning blog-oriented website.
- Technologies: Model View Controller (MVC), MySQL2, Express, Sequelize, Handlebars and dotenv.